Greg Simon Ph.D.

gregorygsimon@gmail.com (805) 746-1668

Professional Summary

Expertise in the practice and theory of state-of-the-art data analysis, modern statistics and mathematics, machine learning, and econometrics. Demonstrated projects utilizing these skill to drive business value in pricing, revenue forecasting, and customer decision modeling. Additional projects in dashboarding, image recognition, and natural language processing. Team-centered, goal-oriented, and driven to succeed.

Project portfolio available at: https://gregorygsimon.github.io

Education

Ph.D. Mathematics, 2016, University of Michigan

M.S. Data Analytics, 2021, Western Governors University

B.A. Mathematics, 2010, University of California, Santa Cruz

• cum laude and highest honors in the major (mathematics)

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, R, SQL, Spark, Julia

Other: AWS Cloud, Git, Docker, Tableau, Google Apps Script, Shell scripting

Certifications: AWS Certification - Machine Learning Specialty (expires 2023, ID#RX11FD2CEB4E1WKF)

Employment Experience

Data Scientist - Bayer Crop Science via Signature Consulting [2020 - Present]

- Completed projects answering business questions in product pricing, revenue forecasting, customer decision modeling, and risk management primarily using R and Python
- Team expert in AWS Cloud Services e.g. developed team data catalog, wrote Lambda functions and structured S3 storage back-end for customer-facing pilot app
- Developed framework for high-dimensional copula correlation modeling used in simulations

Course Faculty in Statistics - Western Governors University [2017 - 2020]

- Teaching applied statistics outstanding student evaluations available upon request
- Gathering and analyzing student data using Python for approx. 1500 active students in our course
- Led machine learning projects aligning course practice problems with positive student outcomes
- Developed dashboard to automate data collection and visualization of student progress
- Developed automation pipeline using SQL for department to message hundreds of students daily

Graduate Student Instructor [2011-2016], Lecturer [2016-2017] University of Michigan

- Primary instructor for calculus series, differential equations and multi-variable calculus
- Course coordinator for Accelerated Precalculus (2 terms), Calculus II

Projects and Workshops

Image recognition 6-week project with TrainX 7/2019 - 9/2019

- Co-lead five student-practitioners developing image recognition model in AWS to predict make and models from images of car from street-facing webcams, in connection with Detroit PD
- Contact: Aubrey Agee, TrainX co-founder, aubrey@trainx.ai

updated: Sep 26, 2021